Seidenberg, Jacob Additional Arbitration Files 5935
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files
1980-1994
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Seidenberg, Jacob
5935
8 cubic feet
8 linear ft.
Records (documents).
3126422
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, October 31, 2014
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 18, 2019
Biographical / Historical
Dr. Jacob Seidenberg (1914-1996) was a government official who specialized in labor arbitration and non-discrimination contracts, and wrote extensively on labor law and negotiations. He graduated from Temple University in 1937 and received a law degree from the University of Pennsylvania Law School in 1941. During the 1940s he was an attorney with the U.S. War Department, the National War Labor Board and the National Wage Stabilization Board. In 1948 he went to graduate school at Cornell University, from which he earned his Ph.D. in industrial and labor relations in 1951. In 1951 he joined the staff of the President's Committee on Government Contract Compliance. The Committee was abolished by President Dwight D. Eisenhower in August 1953 by Executive Order 10479 and was succeeded by the President's Committee on Government Contracts. Seidenberg was appointed Executive Director of the new committee and served until January 1960 when he resigned to become a full-time labor arbitrator. The Committee was responsible for enforcing non-discrimination clauses in government contracts, worked with private businesses to help them overcome job discrimination, and developed educational programs against ethnic and racial discrimination. The chairman was Vice President Richard Nixon, and the vice chairman was Secretary of Labor James P. Mitchell. In later years Seidenberg served on a number of boards of inquiry involving labor disputes. From 1970 to 1975 he was chairman of the Federal Services Impasses Panel which settled deadlocks in federal labor negotiations.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /4039: Milton R. Konvitz Papers /4085: Milton R. Konvitz Additional Papers /4107: Kheel Center Additional Cataloging Project Work notes /4107: Kheel Center Additional Cataloging Project Work notes 5031 A&B: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5032: Jacob Seidenberg Injunction Study 5175: Jacob Seidenberg Taft-Hartley Maritime Dispute Records 5194: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Files 5217: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Case Files 5229: Jacob Seidenberg Additional records 5468: Jacob Seidenberg Arbitration files 5519: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5571: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5583/1: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 1 5605: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Records 5635: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5666: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5706: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5756: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5773: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5808: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5900: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5953: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Records 5988: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 6047: Archives Information File
Arbitration, Industrial--United States--Sources.; Seidenberg, Jacob.
3126422
- Overseas Educ. Assn.. (Box 1)
  - North Central Association of Colleges and Schools, 1990-1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - SAAAAC, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Volume 1: Department of Defense Civilian Personnel, 1982-1990 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Volume 2: Department of Defense Civilian Personnel, 1976-1992 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Overseas Dependents Schools, 1959-1992 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Union Pacific RR / Southern Pacific. (Box 2)
  - Union Pacific Railroad Company Submission Agreement Volume 1, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Union Pacific Railroad Company Submission Agreement Volume 2, 1980-1987 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Union Pacific Railroad Company Submission Agreement Volume 3, 1954-1982 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Union Pacific Railroad Company Submission Agreement Volume 4, 1973-1983 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Union Pacific Railroad Company: Exhibits 12A Through 17D, 1944-1989 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Union Pacific Railroad Company: Proceedings, 1983-1989 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Southern Pacific Transportation Company vs. United Transportation Union: Question At Issue, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - United Transportation Union vs. Southern Pacific Transportation Company: Mediation Agreement, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - United Transportation Union vs. Southern Pacific Transportation Company: Organization's Submission Volume 1, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - United Transportation Union vs. Southern Pacific Transportation Company: Organization's Submission Volume 2, 1987-1990 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - United Transportation Union vs. Southern Pacific Transportation Company: Organization's Submission Volume 3, 1968-1976 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - United Transportation Union vs. Southern Pacific Transportation Company: Exhibits 1 Through 10, 1964-1991 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - United Transportation Union vs. Southern Pacific Transportation Company: Arbitration Proceedings, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Education Association of Charles County vs. Board of Education of Charles County: Impasse Hearing, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Education Association of Charles County vs. Board of Education of Charles County: Exhibits, 1990-1992 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Education Association of Charles County's Initial Proposal (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Education Association of Charles County vs. Board of Education of Charles County: Handwritten Notes, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Education Association of Charles County vs. Board of Education of Charles County: Position Paper, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- EI DuPont; Western Pacific; Southern Pacific; Union Pacific. (Box 3)
  - PL 3742, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - PL 3742, 1984-1992 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - PL 3604, 1984-1990 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - ICC Round- NY Dock, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - UP-MOP New York Dock, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - PL 3604 Case Number 71, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - PL 1348 Case Number 73, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - PL 1348 Case Number 72, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - PL 1348 Case Number 73, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Special Board of Adjustment No. 1002 Case No. 97, 1988-1991 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Special Board of Adjustment No. 1002 Case No. 98, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Eastern Air Lines, Inc. vs. Transport Workers Union of America, AFL-CIO, Local 553, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - DuPont de Nemours and Company vs. United Workers, Inc.: Arbitration Hearing, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - American Federation of Railroad Police vs. National Railroad Passenger Corporation Case No. 1, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - American Federation of Railroad Police vs. National Railroad Passenger Corporation Case No. 2, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Amer. Fed. of Govt Employees; Indiana High Rail; St. Louis Southwest RR Design Corp; Southern Pacific. (Box 4)
  - PLB No. 4948: United Transportation Union vs. St. Louis Southwestern Railroad Company, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - PLB No. 4948: United Transportation Union vs. St. Louis Southwestern Railroad Company, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - PLB No. 4058: United Transportation Union vs. National Railroad Passenger Corporation, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - PLB No. 4058: United Transportation Union vs. National Railroad Passenger Corporation, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - PLB No. 4058: United Transportation Union vs. National Railroad Passenger Corporation, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - PLB No. 3931: Western Railway Supervisors Association vs. Southern Pacific Transportation Company- Eastern Lines, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - PLB No. 4058: United Transportation Union vs. St. Louis Southwestern Railway Company (Cotton Belt), 1989 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - PLB No. 4188: United Railway Supervisors Association vs. Consolidated Rail Corporation, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - PLB No. 4188: United Railway Supervisors Association vs. Consolidated Rail Corporation, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - PLB No. 4188: United Railway Supervisors Association vs. Consolidated Rail Corporation, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - PLB No. 4681: United Transportation Union vs. Indiana Hi-Rail Corporation, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - PLB No. 3604: Brotherhood of Locomotive Engineers vs. Southern Pacific Railroad Company, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - American Federation of Government Employees, 1986-1988 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - PLB No. 3603: United Transportation Union vs. National Railroad Passenger Corporation, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - PLB No. 2448: Brotherhood of Locomotive Engineers vs. Chicago, Milwaukee, St. Paul and Pacific Railroad Company, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Baltimore Ohio; Union Pacific; CSX Transportation. (Box 5)
  - PLB No. 4833, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - PLB No. 4833, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - PLB No. 4833, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - PLB No. 4833, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - PLB No. 4833, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - PLB No. 4833, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - PLB No. 4833, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - PLB No. 4833, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - PLB No. 4833, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - PLB No. 4833, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - PLB No. 1348, 1983-1987 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Overseas Education Assn.. (Box 6)
  - Overseas Education Association vs. Department of Defense Dependent Schools: Fact-Finding Hearing Volume I, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Overseas Education Association vs. Department of Defense Dependent Schools: Fact-Finding Hearing Volume II, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Overseas Education Association vs. Department of Defense Dependent Schools: Fact-Finding Hearing Volume III, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Overseas Education Association vs. Department of Defense Dependent Schools: Fact-Finding Hearing Volume IV, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Overseas Education Association vs. Department of Defense Dependent Schools: Fact-Finding Hearing Volume V, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Report and Recommendations of Fact Finder in Bargaining, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Overseas Education Association Salary and Benefits Agreements, 1989-1992 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Overseas Education Association Salary and Benefits Agreements, 1991-1992 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Overseas Education Association Salary and Benefits Agreements, 1988-1994 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Overseas Education Association Salary and Benefits Agreements, 1988-1994 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Washington Gas; DC Dept. of Corrections; BF Goodrich; Harbism Walker; Capitol Printing; Mountainside Transport; Various Brazilian Airlines & others. (Box 7)
  - IAMAW vs. Varig Airlines Arbitration Transcription Volume I, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - IAMAW vs. Varig Airlines Arbitration Transcription Volume II, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - IAMAW vs. Varig Airlines Arbitration Transcription Volume III-IV, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - IAMAW vs. Varig Airlines Labor Arbitration Transcription, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - P.L. 4970 AMTRAK-IAMAW, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - USCO Inc. - L570-IBT FMCS-90-13345, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Walker- Harbison- USA FMSC Case No. 90-14508, 1980-1990 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - GPO - Columbia Typographical Union, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - B.F. Goodrich - UPIU - L - 1449 FMCS 89-21798, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - WGS-OPEIU-Local No. 2, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - DC Department of Corrections IBT Local 1714 FMCS Case No. 88-21515, 1989-1990 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - CAPICO-GCIUL- 449, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - CSX Transportation, Inc.-IAMAW, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Hall Container Line Inc. Local 333-United Marine Division, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Mountainside Transport, Inc. Truck Drivers and Helpers L 355 AAA Case No. 14-300-1447-89-Q, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Varig Brazilian-IAMAW District 100 - RUGEN GR, 1988-1990 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Typographical Union Exhibits, 1988-1989 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Union Pacific. (Box 8)
  - PLB No. 4561 Case No. 1, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - PLB No. 4561 Case No. 2, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - PLB No. 4561 Case No. 2, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - PLB No. 4561 Case No. 3, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - PLB No. 4561 Case No. 5, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - PLB No. 4561 Case No. 6, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - PLB No. 4561 Case No. 8, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - PLB No. 4561 Case No. 10, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - PLB No. 4561 Case No. 11, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - PLB No. 4561 Case No. 12, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - PLB No. 4561 Case No. 13, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - PLB No. 4561 Case No. 14, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - PLB No. 4561 Case No. 15, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - PLB No. 4561 Case No. 16-20, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 14)